ILGWU Local 155 Records 5780/129
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 155 Records
1970-1972
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 155
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/129
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
The collection contains records relating to Local 155's elections in 1971 and the investigations of those elections the following year.
5508504
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, August 10, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Local 155, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union ILGWU), also known as the Knitgoods Workers' Union, was chartered in 1933 and based in New York City.
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the appeal of February 1971 officer elections for Local 155. Edward Tucker was a rank and file candidate running for manager-secretary of Local 155. He filed multiple appeals regarding the results of the elections on behalf of the Rank and File slate regarding candidate nominations, favored candidates, and the use of intimidation, harassment and fear of penalty for support the Rank and File candidates. The collection includes hearing transcripts, documentation of the numerous appeals and protests, records of the Election and Objection Committee, and correspondence. Another election took place in March 1972 conducted by the U.S. Labor Department after investigations into the fraud charges.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/054: ILGWU Local 155 Records
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Women's clothing industry--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Industrial relations--United States.; Industrial relations--New York (State)--New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 155 (New York, N.Y.)
5508504
- 1971 Local 155 Election, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  U.S. Department of Labor Investigation
- Rank and File Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Local 155 Elections, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Protest-Appeal of Edward J. Tucker. 1971 Local 155 Elections. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Progressive Group Knitgoods Workers' Union, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Election and Objection Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Local 155 Elections, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  English and Spanish
- Local 155 Re-Run Election, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1971 Local 155 Election Results, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1971 Local 155 Elections. Rank and File Committee Protest, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)